Episode 23
에피소드 23
I don't mind being sold.
나는 팔려도 상관없다.
Since my mom passed away...
엄마가 돌아가신 이후로..
It makes no difference to me where.
어느 곳이든 나에게는 아무런 차이가 없습니다 .
Sometimes my dad speaks...
가끔 아빠가 말을 하기도 하는데..
About my deceased mother...
돌아가신 어머니에 대해서...
And women are jealous...
그리고 여자는 질투한다...
So he sold me to a rich merchant...
그래서 그는 나를 부유한 상인에게 팔았습니다...
The famous Mr. Lee.
그 유명한 리 씨.
famous?
유명한?
The Lee family is about to buy a bunch of new kids...
리 가족은 새로운 아이들을 잔뜩 사려고 하는데 ...
sometimes.
가끔씩.
The ones I bought before...
그전에 사온 애들은 ..
All rolled up in a grass mat...
모두 잔디 매트에 말아서 ...
They were thrown into mass graves .
대량 무덤 에 던져졌습니다 .
Stop talking! Move quickly!
그만 떠들어라! 빨리 움직여!
They abused the child?
그들이 아이를 학대했다고요?
Not only abuse...
학대뿐만 아니라...
They are even treated like animals.
심지어 동물 취급을 받기도 합니다.
Now, try applying more blusher.
자, 블러셔를 더 발라보세요.
He treats me like a dog.
그는 나를 개처럼 대합니다.
When the wind is good...
바람이 좋을때..
He'll make us fight...
그 사람이 우리를 싸우게 만들 거야...
And only the last person gets to eat.
그리고 마지막 사람만이 먹을 수 있습니다.
If we don't fight...
우리가 싸우지 않는다면...
He will whip us.
그는 우리를 채찍질할 것이다.
The louder we cry and scream...
우리가 더 크게 울고 비명을 지를수록...
run!
달리다!
The more he does this, the more excited and happy he becomes.
그럴수록 그는 더욱 신나고 행복해집니다.
Often the servants did not eat their food ...
종종 하인들은 음식을 먹지 않았습니다 ...
With serious injuries.
심각한 부상을 당하면서.
If they die...
그들이 죽으면...
They will be removed.
그것들은 제거될 것입니다.
Where did you get that scar ?
그 흉터는 어디서 났나요?
You don't need to know the details.
세부 사항을 알 필요는 없습니다.
All you need to know is that I finally got away.
당신이 알아야 할 것은 내가 마침내 도망 쳤다는 것입니다.
The person who makes the decisions at home is Mr. Lee.
집에서 결정을 내리는 사람은 리 씨입니다 .
He is old...
그는 늙었다...
So he can't move fast.
그래서 그는 빨리 움직일 수 없습니다.
So I succeeded in escaping.
그래서 나는 탈출에 성공했다.
I'm afraid they'll find me...
그 사람들이 나를 찾을까 봐 두려워요...
So I set the house on fire.
그래서 집에 불을 질렀어요.
turns off the light!
불을 끄다!
- fast! - turns off the light!
- 빠른! - 불을 끄다!
Come on, get some water!
자, 물 좀 가져와!
- fast!
- 빠른!
- fast! there! - The water is coming.
- 빠른! 거기! - 물이 오고 있어요.
be careful.
조심하세요.
You again!
당신이 다시!
You are a strong and healthy person. Go to work for food.
당신은 강하고 건강한 사람입니다. 음식을 위해 일하러 가십시오.
go! Don't interfere with my work.
가다! 내 일을 방해하지 마세요.
Get out of here!
여기서 떠나세요!
After running away, he collapsed on the street.
도망친 뒤 길에 쓰러졌습니다.
- I became a beggar. - go!
- 나는 거지가 되었습니다. - 가다!
I don't want to go back there again.
나는 그곳으로 다시 돌아가고 싶지 않습니다.
One day, a carpenter named Wei Xian...
어느 날, 웨이시안이라는 목수에게 ...
Look at me on the street
길거리에서 나 좀 봐
And he said I had talent.
그리고 나한테 재능이 있다고 하더군요.
He wants to hire me as his apprentice.
그는 나를 견습생으로 고용하고 싶어합니다.
I realize...
나는 깨닫는다...
The richer you become...
부자가 될수록...
The more they do this, the more unreasonable they become.
그럴수록 그들은 불합리해진다.
I made it according to their needs ...
그 분들의 필요 에 따라 만들어 봤는데 ..
But they say it's not right now .
그런데 지금은 안 맞는다고 하더라고요.
Do you remember that they can step on my head?
그들이 내 머리를 밟을 수 있다는 것을 기억하나요 ?
Don't expect me to accept...
내가 받아들일 거라고 기대하지 마세요...
Please order again!
다시 주문하세요!
Useless boy!
쓸모없는 소년!
I must leave you beggar.
나는 당신을 거지로 놔둬야합니다.
Protecting your dog is better than protecting yourself.
개를 보호하는 것이 자신을 보호하는 것보다 낫습니다.
At least the dogs know...
적어도 개들은 알아요...
Flip it over and make me happy.
뒤집어서 나를 행복하게 해주세요.
What can you do?
당신은 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
Are you upset?
너 삐졌어?
Are you still mute?
아직 벙어리인가요?
Say something!
뭐라고 말해보세요!
It's fun to show that sad face!
그 슬픈 얼굴을 보여주는 것은 재미있다!
Do you want to get hit?
맞고 싶나요?
Wei Xian is not a good person.
Wei Xian은 좋은 사람이 아닙니다.
He loves to abuse.
그는 학대하는 것을 좋아합니다.
He never thought of us as human beings.
그는 결코 우리를 인간이라고 생각하지 않았습니다.
He always gets angry at them...
그는 항상 그들에게 화를 낸다...
Hot-tempered and stubborn.
화끈하고 완고함.
Work diligently.
부지런히 일하십시오.
Okay, ma'am.
좋아요, 부인.
Hold it with your hand.
손으로 잡으십시오.
What are you seeing?
무엇을 보고 있나요?
I told him to hold it with his hand.
손으로 잡으라고 했어요.
Do you want to get hit again?
또 맞고 싶나요?
wait.
기다리다.
interesting.
흥미로운.
fast!
빠른!
wait!
기다리다!
Work diligently! Grab it with your hands!
부지런히 일하세요! 손으로 잡아!
That person tied me up...
그 사람이 나를 묶었는데...
With his hidden weapons and chains.
그의 숨겨진 무기와 사슬 로 .
He only feeds me once every few days.
그는 며칠에 한 번만 나에게 먹이를줍니다.
He did that to control me.
그 사람은 나를 조종하려고 그런 짓을 한 거예요.
Remember, I fed you...
기억해, 내가 너한테 먹였어...
then you are my dog
그럼 넌 내 개야
When I try to run again...
다시 달리려고 하면...
Don't expect to be able to remove things...
물건을 제거할 수 있을 거라 기대하지 마세요 ...
Around the neck.
목 주위.
Yet I did not bow down and beg for mercy.
그럼에도 나는 엎드려 자비를 구하지 않았습니다.
I was trying to open the mango...
망고를 열려고 했는데..
I hope to escape.
탈출을 희망합니다.
One day...
어느 날...
I opened the mango...
망고를 열었는데..
And ran away.
그리고 도망갔습니다.
I don't like hearing people talk...
나는 사람들이 말하는 것을 듣는 것을 좋아하지 않습니다 ...
I'm handsome...
나는 잘 생겼다...
Because I know they have bad intentions .
그들이 나쁜 의도를 가지고 있다는 것을 알기 때문입니다 .
But if you say he's handsome...
그런데 잘생겼다고 하면...
I'm so happy...
나 무지 행복해...
Because I know you praise me.
왜냐하면 나는 당신이 나를 칭찬한다는 것을 알고 있기 때문입니다.
How about this bracelet?...
이 팔찌 어때요?...
And the blacksmith?
그리고 대장장이?
all right...
알겠어요...
Miss was unarmed and almost injured ..
비무장 상태로 부상 을 입을 뻔한 미스 ..
During ancestor worship ceremonies.
조상 숭배 행사 중.
That thought occurred to me...
그 생각이 들었습니다...
About Wei Xian's impeccable craftsmanship.
Wei Xian 의 완벽한 장인 정신 에 대해 .
I found him and forgot the past.
나는 그를 찾았고 과거를 잊었습니다.
I want to buy a hidden weapon...
숨은무기 사고싶다...
Suitable for women.
여성에게 적합합니다.
where?
어디?
Because you are here...
당신이 여기 있기 때문에 ...
Why are you leaving in such a hurry?
왜 서둘러 떠나는 거야?
After all, I was your master.
어쨌든 나는 너의 주인이었어.
I have looked after you for years.
나는 몇 년 동안 당신을 돌보았습니다 .
How can I raise a dog that doesn't care...
개의치 않는 강아지를 어떻게 키울 수 있을까요 ...
With you?
너 같이?
If it weren't for me...
내가 아니었다면...
You have been starving for a long time.
당신은 오랫동안 굶주렸습니다.
Now you're back...
이제 돌아왔구나...
Shouldn't you pay off your debt?
빚을 갚아야 하지 않겠습니까 ?
You should know.
당신은 알고 있어야.
Those who betray their masters...
주인을 배반하는 자들 ...
You won't get any attention...
주목을 받지 못할 것이다...
Even though he was beaten to death by his owner.
비록 주인에게 맞아 죽었지만.
I can never open it...
절대 열 수 없어요...
A mechanism I designed.
내가 디자인한 메커니즘.
But if you worship me and repent...
그러나 너희가 나를 숭배 하고 뉘우친다면...
Maybe I can show mercy...
어쩌면 내가 자비를 베풀 수도 있겠지...
For our relationship it is master and follower.
우리의 관계를 위해서 그것은 주인과 추종자입니다.
I am not the person you used to know.
나는 당신이 알던 그런 사람이 아닙니다 .
Open the door or I will kill you.
문을 열지 않으면 내가 당신을 죽일 것입니다.
open the door
문을 열어라.
He ambushed me...
그 사람이 나를 매복 공격했어요...
With his hidden weapon.
그의 숨겨진 무기로.
I succeeded in avoiding it...
피하는데 성공했는데...
But I was injured by that weapon...
그런데 그 무기 때문에 부상을 당했어요 ...
And they become victims of their own evil deeds.
그리고 자신의 악행의 희생자가 됩니다 .
You never said...
당신은 말한 적이 없습니다 ...
Your village is in Huiyang District.
Huiyang District에 있는 당신의 마을.
You said you would never return.
당신은 결코 돌아오지 않을 것이라고 말했습니다.
Then don't say anything ...
그럼 아무 말도 하지 마세요 ...
When I give you a mission?
내가 너에게 임무를 줄 때?
Huarongzhou, I’m sorry.
화룽저우 씨, 미안해요.
How much...
얼마나 많이...
Lady, don't do that...
아가씨, 그러지 마세요...
Girl, don't cry.
아가씨, 울지 마세요.
I know I was wrong.
나는 내가 잘못했다는 것을 안다.
- But don't worry about me. - no...
- 하지만 내 걱정은 하지 마세요. - 아니요...
This is my fault.
이건 내 잘못이야.
It's not all your fault.
그것은 모두 당신의 잘못이 아닙니다.
don't worry.
걱정 하지마.
I won't leave you in trouble.
나는 당신을 곤경에 빠뜨리지 않을 것입니다 .
great.
좋아요.
It doesn't matter who the leader is here...
여기 리더가 누구인지는 상관없어요 ...
But my bodyguard was not found guilty.
하지만 내 경호원은 유죄 판결을 받지 않았습니다.
If you torture me again...
또 고문하면...
I will check with the officials...
관계자들을 확인하겠습니다 ..
Corporal punishment does not lead to release.
체벌로는 석방되지 않습니다.
Miss Hua, who is there...
미스 후아, 거기 있는 사람...
not cooperating
협력하지 않음
In the end we can't do anything.
결국 우리는 아무것도 할 수 없습니다.
We just follow instructions.
우리는 지시를 따를 뿐입니다.
Please pass on my warning to those on duty...
내 경고를 당직자에게 전달하세요...
So that he can evaluate the situation.
그 사람이 이 상황을 평가할 수 있도록 말이죠.
Did he disappear without a trace?
흔적도 없이 사라졌나요?
After the owner returned and gave instructions...
주인이 돌아와 지시를 내린 후...
I sent a guard ...
경비병 을 보냈는데 ...
Outside the walls of the Financial Supervisory Service...
금감원 담장 밖...
But the couple was nowhere to be seen.
하지만 그 부부의 모습은 전혀 보이지 않았습니다.
I also looked at almost every tea shop, but...
저도 거의 모든 찻집을 찾아봤지만 ..
And these days, boarding houses...
그리고 요즘 하숙집도 ...
But I have absolutely no clue.
하지만 전혀 단서가 없습니다.
Maybe our guards can't afford that.
어쩌면 우리 경비원이 그럴 여유가 없을 수도 있습니다.
But we can't do anything...
하지만 우리는 아무것도 할 수 없습니다...
Because we can only do it in secret.
왜냐하면 우리는 비밀리에만 할 수 있기 때문입니다.
Teacher Hua, what are we asking?
Hua 선생님, 우리는 무엇을 요구합니까?
Don magistrate's help?
돈 치안 판사의 도움?
He should investigate...
그 사람이 조사해봐야지...
here.
여기.
He was able to investigate more thoroughly .
그는 더욱 철저하게 조사할 수 있었다 .
Magistrate Wang will not accept my orders.
왕 치안판사는 내 명령을 받아들이지 않을 것입니다 .
Qianzhi, ikut saya ke Taman Zhong.
Qianzhi, ikut saya ke Taman Zhong.
Okay, ma'am.
좋아요, 부인.
Taman species
타만 종
Teacher, Teacher Hua is here.
선생님, Hua 선생님이 오셨습니다.
Kian!
키안!
Tuan.
투안.
help...
도와주세요...
A wealthy merchant, Mr. Are you looking for Li?
부유한 상인 Mr. Li를 찾고 계십니까?
You rarely come to see me.
당신은 나를 보러 오는 경우가 거의 없습니다.
I remember you came looking for me.
당신이 나를 찾으러 온 것을 기억합니다.
Hua Rongzhou's work is more complicated...
Hua Rongzhou의 일은 더 복잡합니다 ...
More than we thought.
우리가 생각했던 것보다.
Mr. and Mrs. Lee just disappeared.
리 부부가 방금 사라졌습니다.
Clearly they are hiding something.
분명히 그들은 뭔가를 숨기고 있습니다.
This shows that not everything they say is true.
이는 그들이 말하는 것이 모두 사실이 아님을 보여줍니다.
I said. His name is Qi Rongzhou...
나는 말했다. 그 사람 이름은 Qi Rongzhou...
But you still call him Hua Rongzhou.
하지만 당신은 아직도 그를 화룽저우(Hua Rongzhou)라고 부릅니다.
Want to show who you support?
당신이 누구 에게 찬성하는지 보여주고 싶나요 ?
He is my bodyguard.
그는 나의 경호원입니다.
He saved me from danger many times .
그는 나를 위험에서 여러 번 구해주었습니다.
I can't just leave it...
그냥 놔둘 수가 없어요...
He was slandered and treated badly.
그는 중상을 당하고 나쁜 대우를 받았습니다.
security?
경비원?
The way he looks at you...
그 사람이 당신을 보는 방식은...
It's different from security guards.
경비원과 다르지 않습니다.
So you know...
그러니까 알잖아...
But you kept him by your side.
하지만 당신은 그를 당신 옆에 두었습니다.
Who am I to you?
나는 당신에게 누구입니까?
Just reporting the facts...
사실을 보도할 뿐입니다...
Tentang Qi Rongzhou.
Tentang Qi Rongzhou.
Lin Jiang's investigation is not parallel...
Lin Jiang의 조사는 평행하지 않습니다 ...
With permission.
허가를 받아.
Don't you want to hear my explanation?
내 설명을 듣고 싶지 않아?
These are his words.
이것이 그의 말입니다.
You believe what the guard tells you .
당신은 경비원이 당신에게 말하는 것을 믿습니다 .
Why can't I believe what the guard tells me?
경비원이 나에게 말하는 것을 왜 믿을 수 없습니까 ?
It seems...
것 같다...
You have a grudge against Hua Rongzhou ...
당신은 Hua Rongzhou에 대해 원한을 가지고 있습니다 ...
So I understand...
그래서 이해해요...
In my words Mr. Sansi.
내 말로 Sansi 씨.
are you okay.
괜찮아.
I will collect the evidence myself.
증거는 제가 직접 수집하겠습니다.
You will see the right side and the wrong side.
당신은 올바른 면 과 잘못된 면을 보게 될 것입니다.
But before being found guilty...
하지만 유죄판결을 받기 전...
I hope you don't give instructions ...
지시를 내리지 않기를 바랍니다 ...
To torture him illegally.
그를 불법적으로 고문하려고요.
Kian.
키안.
Can you...
할 수 있나요...
see you...
만나요...
Because you want to see me...
네가 나를 보고 싶어하니까...
At least once?
적어도 한 번은?
Tuan.
투안.
Next time, can you think of me?
다음에는 내 생각 좀 해줄래?
Before acting?
연기하기 전에?
There are several ways to convey your commands .
귀하의 명령을 전달하는 방법에는 여러 가지가 있습니다 .
Why did you do that?
왜 그런 짓을 한거야?
What are you seeing?
무엇을 보고 있나요?
Bakjong is too big for me.
박종은 나에게 너무 크다.
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
I want to tell you something.
나는 당신에게 뭔가를 말하고 싶어.
I said everything I wanted to say, sir.
제가 하고 싶은 말은 다 했습니다 , 선생님.
We're on a busy road.
우리는 바쁜 길을 가고 있습니다.
I don't want to be seen talking to you.
나는 당신과 이야기하는 모습을 보이고 싶지 않습니다 .
If so, I will wait for you at the teahouse in front.
그렇다면 앞의 찻집에서 기다리겠습니다.
If you want to help the guards...
경비병을 돕고 싶다면...
Go ahead and try it
어서 해봐요
Go to the teahouse in advance.
미리 찻집에 가보세요.
Okay, ma'am.
좋아요, 부인.
Go and guard the door...
가서 문을 지키세요...
But leave the door open...
하지만 문은 열어두세요...
Only then can we maintain morality.
그래야 우리가 도덕을 유지할 수 있습니다.
Yes, it's full.
예, 가득 찼습니다.
I heard it from Nanfeng...
난펑한테 들었는데...
You don't mind him marrying Qianzhi .
당신은 그가 Qianzhi와 결혼하는 것을 꺼리지 않습니다 .
This is between the two.
이것은 둘 사이의 일입니다.
I won't interfere.
나는 방해하지 않습니다.
We just launched Qianzhi.
방금 Qianzhi를 출시했습니다.
He is free to choose the direction of his life.
그는 인생의 방향을 자유롭게 선택할 수 있습니다 .
Sir, someone mentioned...
선생님, 어떤 분이 언급하셨는데...
About helping my guards early.
내 경비병을 일찍 돕는 것에 대해 .
Can you tell me more now?
이제 더 자세히 말해주실 수 있나요 ?
I heard about your security guard.
당신의 경비원에 대해 들었습니다.
I know you're trying to find...
당신이 찾으려고 노력하고 있다는 걸 알아요...
A merchant couple.
상인 부부.
It took a long time...
시간이 오래 걸렸어요...
But I found out his latest address.
하지만 그 사람 의 최근 주소를 알아냈어요.
Where are they?
그들은 어디에 있나요?
What are the conditions? speaking.
조건은 무엇입니까? 발언.
When I checked the couple's location...
커플의 위치를 ​​확인해보니..
It's not because you want to take advantage.
당신이 이점을 취하고 싶어서가 아닙니다.
It's not that easy.
그렇게 쉬운 일이 아닙니다.
Nanfeng happened to appear that day...
그날 우연히 난펑이 나타났는데...
Mr. Zhong drove you home.
종씨가 당신을 집까지 모셔다 드렸습니다.
I know that...
그렇게 알아요...
That person likes you.
그 사람이 당신을 좋아한다고요.
If it's because of the guards...
경비병 때문이라면...
It is best not to get involved any further.
더 이상 관여하지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
You want me to ignore it...
내가 무시하길 바라시는데...
Unjust people...
억울한 사람들...
To protect myself?
나 자신을 보호하기 위해?
Your guards are absolutely killer.
당신의 경비원은 정말 죽인다.
He was not abused.
그는 학대를 당하지 않았습니다.
It depends on who died.
누가 죽었는지에 따라 다릅니다.
If you are that person...
당신이 그 사람이라면...
Can you still say that?
아직도 그렇게 말할 수 있어?
I just realized, you...
방금 깨달았어, 당신은...
Very eloquent.
매우 웅변적이다.
Where are the couple now?
그 부부는 지금 어디에 있나요?
OK. You have to see it for yourself.
괜찮은. 직접 보아야 합니다.
5 miles south of town...
마을에서 남쪽으로 5마일...
There are abandoned areas.
버려진 지역이 있습니다.
It was occupied a few days ago.
며칠 전에는 점유되었습니다.
thank you
감사합니다.
I will repay you someday .
언젠가 는 보답하겠습니다 .
not needed. Consider this in return ...
필요 없음. 그 대가로 이것을 고려하십시오 ...
For saving my life.
내 생명을 구해줘서.
great.
좋아요.
We are tied now.
우리는 지금 묶여 있습니다.
I'm not qualified...
난 자격이 없어...
say so
그렇게 말해
Right away...
바로 종박...
Because I'm too busy.
너무 바빠서.
If you want a quiet life...
조용한 삶을 원하신다면 ..
You shouldn't go near that person.
그 사람 근처에 가면 안 돼.
When I said I wanted to approach that person ?
내가 그 사람에게 접근하고 싶다고 말했을 때 ?
We can both consider...
우리 둘 다 고려할 수 있습니다 ...
To contact information.
연락처로.
Because you are sure...
확신하고 계시니까...
You don't want my protection...
내 보호를 원하지 않아...
I won't force you anymore.
더 이상 강요하지 않겠습니다.
I respect your choice.
나는 당신의 선택을 존중합니다.
If you need my help...
내 도움이 필요하다면...
Come see me...
나를 보러 와라...
I won't say no.
나는 거절하지 않을 것입니다.
thank you
감사합니다.
Kian.
키안.
See you later.
또 보자.
Miss, it's late.
아가씨, 늦었어요.
How about we go tomorrow?
우리 내일 가는 게 어때요?
no.
아니요.
Tell Huang to bring some people.
황 에게 사람들을 데려오라고 말하세요 .
We will take action as quickly as possible...
최대한 빨리 조치해드리겠습니다 ...
To avoid trouble.
문제를 피하기 위해.
don't worry. I told him the address.
걱정 하지마. 나는 그에게 주소를 말했다.
I didn't ask him about it.
나는 그에 대해 묻지 않았습니다.
Find out about that person's personality...
그 사람의 성격을 알아보세요..
He won't put his guards in jail
그는 그의 경비병을 감옥에 가두지 않을 것이다
It should be longer than it should be.
원래보다 길어야합니다.
He's probably on his way out of town right now.
그 사람은 아마 지금 시내를 나가는 중일 거예요 .
Do you want to see him?
그를 보고 싶나요?
me...
나...
Why would I want to do that?
내가 왜 그런 일을 하고 싶나요?
Every time we meet...
만날 때마다...
you will fight
너는 싸울 것이다
You might not get a chance...
기회가 없을 수도 있습니다...
To talk to each other again.
다시 서로 이야기를 나누기 위해 .
You both hold a grudge against each other.
당신은 둘 다 서로에 대해 원한을 품고 있습니다 .
I hope you both resolve this misunderstanding .
두 분 모두 이 오해를 해결하시길 바랍니다 .
Otherwise, the resentment may become worse later on.
그렇지 않으면 나중에 원한이 더 심해질 수 있습니다.
I released that person...
그 사람을 풀어줬는데...
But I can't give it to him...
하지만 난 그 사람에게 줄 수가 없어요...
Satisfactory answer.
만족스러운 답변.
Even though I gave it to that person...
그 사람한테 줬는데도..
Useful information...
유용한 정보...
It might not be enough...
충분하지 않을 수도 있습니다 ...
To get rid of his hatred towards me .
나에 대한 그의 증오를 없애기 위해 .
If you look at that person now...
지금 그 사람을 보면...
That person probably despises me.
그 사람은 아마 나를 경멸할 거예요.
Because she was willing to let him go ...
그녀가 기꺼이 그를 놓아주었기 때문에 ...
That doesn't mean he isn't satisfied...
그렇다고 그가 만족하지 않는다는 뜻은 아닙니다 ...
With your findings.
귀하의 조사 결과와 함께.
Can your horse still run?
당신의 말은 아직도 달릴 수 있나요?
Absolutely.
틀림없이.
I take good care of it.
나는 그것을 잘 돌본다.
Running up to this point should not cause any problems.
여기까지 실행해도 아무런 문제가 발생하지 않습니다.
Lady, this is the place.
아가씨, 여기가 바로 그 곳이에요.
So far I haven't been able to find the location...
지금까지는 위치를 찾을 수 없었습니다 ...
Because I'm hiding...
숨어있으니까...
In an abandoned house.
버려진 집에서.
Surround the house and break down the door.
집을 둘러싸고 문을 부수십시오.
Okay, ma'am!
좋아요, 부인!
Catch them!
그들을 잡아!
All right!
알겠습니다!
Get out!
나가세요!
- What are you doing? - go!
- 뭐하세요? - 가다!
- Do not fight! road name! - Let go!
- 싸우지 마세요! 도로! - 놔줘!
Let me go!
날 보내줘!
How much.
얼마나 많이.
Why did you come here in the middle of the night?
왜 이렇게 한밤중에 여기에 왔나요 ?
Are you here to kill us?
우리를 죽이러 왔나요?
If I come to kill you...
내가 당신을 죽이러 온다면...
Do you think there's still a chance?
아직 기회가 있다고 생각하시나요?
Should I kneel down and talk?
무릎 꿇고 얘기 좀 할까?
You are slandering my guard on the side of the road...
길가에서 내 경비병을 비방하는구나 ...
For no reason that day.
그날 아무 이유 없이.
Then, while I wasn't paying attention, you ran away.
그러다가 내가 관심을 두지 않는 동안 당신은 도망쳤어요 .
Now I'm here to clarify the situation.
이제 상황을 분명히 하러 왔습니다 .
Lady, everything I said is true.
아가씨, 제가 말한 것은 모두 사실입니다.
I am not disparaging him.
나는 그를 비방하지 않습니다.
If everything you say is true...
당신이 말하는 모든 것이 사실이라면...
You will be taken to court...
당신은 법정에 서게 될 것입니다 ...
Instead of hiding in this abandoned house.
이 버려진 집에 숨는 대신 .
Tie your legs and break them...
다리를 묶고 부러뜨리고..
If you try to run away again.
또 도망치려고 하면.
They slandered the Hua family.
그들은 Hua 가족을 비방했습니다.
I can't stay quiet.
나는 조용히 있을 수 없다.
- Yes ma'am! - Lady, please listen to me.
- 네 부인! - 아가씨, 내 말 좀 들어주세요.
We do not dare to offend ...
우리는 감히 기분을 상하게하지 않습니다 ...
Hua family's feelings, young lady.
Hua 가족의 감정, 아가씨.
Don't you dare?
감히하지 않습니까?
Qi Rongzhou is my bodyguard.
Qi Rongzhou는 나의 경호원입니다.
You ruined my reputation by slandering him .
당신은 그를 비방하여 내 평판을 망쳤습니다 .
What are you waiting for? sun!
당신은 무엇을 기다리고 있습니까? 해!
- Lady, don't kill me! - No, it's okay!
- 아가씨, 저를 죽이지 마세요! - 아니요 괜찮아요!
- No!
- 하지 않다!
It is useless energy that makes you evil in the first place.
애초에 당신을 악하게 만드는 것은 쓸모없는 기입니다.
Diam!
디암!
- Someone told me to come here. - shut up!
- 누군가가 여기로 오라고 했어요. - 입 다물어!
I know someone told you to come here.
누군가가 당신에게 여기로 오라고 말한 것을 압니다 .
There's no need to try to hide it.
그것을 숨기려고 할 필요는 없습니다.
I won't ask about that.
그것에 대해서는 묻지 않겠습니다.
You shouldn't curse that person...
그 사람을 욕하면 안 되는데...
While you were wrong.
당신이 잘못한 동안.
I am here to demand justice for Qi Rongzhou.
나는 Qi Rongzhou에 대한 정의를 요구하기 위해 왔습니다 .
Everything we said is true.
우리가 말한 모든 것은 사실입니다.
It's not defamation.
명예훼손이 아닙니다.
It is true that Qi is useless...
Qi가 쓸모없다는 것은 사실이다...
No... I mean, Qi burned down the house...
아니... 내 말은, Qi가 집을 불태웠다는 거죠...
And kill my father-in-law.
그리고 내 시아버지를 죽여라.
How dare you mention this?
감히 이걸 언급하다니.
Don't you know your father-in-law...
시아버지를 모르시나요 ...
What about him?
그 사람은 어때?
Do I really have to say it...
꼭 말해야 하나...
How many slaves and children did he kill?
그가 죽인 노예와 아이들의 수는 얼마나 됩니까 ?
Qi Rongzhou did not report this...
Qi Rongzhou는 이것을보고하지 않았습니다 ...
But you came all this way to accuse him.
그런데 당신은 그를 고발하려고 여기까지 왔습니다.
I should be thankful...
감사해야지...
Your father-in-law has passed away.
당신의 시아버지는 돌아가셨습니다.
Otherwise the person will suffer...
그렇지 않으면 그 사람은 고통받을 것입니다 ...
It's worse than dead.
죽은 것보다 더 나쁘다.
What your father-in-law did was not your fault...
시아버지가 한 일은 네 잘못이 아니다...
But you have to go to court...
하지만 법원에 가야 해...
Explain...
설명하기...
And withdraw the indictment.
그리고 기소장을 철회하라.
Admit your mistakes...
실수를 인정하세요...
I will forget this.
나는 이것을 잊어버릴 것이다.
actually
실제로
Hesitating?
망설이다?
Do you think it's possible to cheat in court?
법정에서 부정행위를 할 수 있다고 생각하시나요 ?
And don't miss me?
그리고 나 놓치지 마세요?
Your hometown is in Hueyang County.
당신의 고향은 회양현에 있습니다.
Believe it or not, you can catch it...
믿거나 말거나 잡을 수 있어요...
Now the whole family...
이제 온 가족이...
Cut yourself off...
몸을 잘라라...
Then they throw it into the river and use it as food for fish.
그리고 그것을 강에 던져서 물고기 먹이로 삼습니다.
No, ma'am.
아니요, 부인.
But I don't think the truth will help.
그러나 나는 진실이 도움이 될 것이라고 생각하지 않습니다 .
Don't be stupid.
바보같은 소리 하지 마세요.
This is my second time...
이번이 두 번째인데...
You prevent your wife from speaking.
당신은 아내가 말을 못하게 막습니다.
Do you remember I'm blind?
내가 장님인 거 기억나?
People are threatening to kill us...
사람들이 우리를 죽이겠다고 위협하고 있어요...
As soon as I came in.
들어오자마자.
I think it's a miss...
미스인 것 같은데...
without seeking the truth
진실을 구하지 않고
It doesn't matter if we say there is no difference.
우리가 차이가 없다고 말하는 것은 중요하지 않습니다 .
I already know the truth...
나는 이미 진실을 알고 있습니다..
Then why should I ask?
그럼 내가 왜 물어봐야 하는데?
Both are deceiving others...
둘 다 남을 속이고 있어요...
For your own sake.
당신 자신을 위해서.
You have been given a chance...
당신에게 기회가 주어졌습니다..
To be honest...
솔직히 말하자면...
And save yourself.
그리고 자신을 구하십시오.
But, if you refuse to say anything...
하지만, 아무 말도 거부한다면...
It doesn't matter which method you use...
어떤 방법을 사용해도 상관이 없습니다...
Then go to court...
그럼 법원으로 가세요...
I withdraw the lawsuit.
소송을 철회합니다.
All nobles are the same.
귀족은 다 똑같습니다.
They refuse to listen to anyone.
그들은 누구의 말도 듣기를 거부합니다 .
They do whatever they want.
그들은 원하는 대로 행동합니다.
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
To tell the truth...
사실대로 말하면...
Can we really forget the past?
정말 과거를 잊을 수 있을까...
And don't disturb my family?
그리고 우리 가족을 방해하지 마세요?
I promise.
약속해요.
We live happily in Huiyang County.
우리는 후이양현에서 행복하게 살고 있습니다 .
As you said, my father...
네 말대로 아버지는...
We know his character.
우리는 그의 성격을 알고 있습니다.
Walaupun kami benci Qi Rongzhou...
Walaupun kami benci Qi Rongzhou...
And find out where he is...
그리고 그 사람이 어디에 있는지 알아내세요...
We want to hide from him...
우리는 그에게서 숨고 싶어...
Instead of looking for him.
그를 찾는 대신.
We won't come this far.
우리는 여기까지 오지 않을 것입니다.
We love our lives.
우리는 우리의 삶을 사랑합니다.
We explained it from the beginning.
우리는 처음부터 그것을 설명했습니다.
We don't want to prolong this.
우리는 이것을 연장하고 싶지 않습니다.
But now we must bear witness to it.
하지만 이제 우리는 그에 대해 증언해야 합니다.
We want to leave Hwangcheong...
우리는 황청을 떠나고 싶다...
But I'm worried about my family's safety...
하지만 우리 가족의 안전은 걱정돼요 ...
When you return...
당신이 돌아올 때...
So we hid.
그래서 우리는 숨었습니다.
We remember to wait...
우리는 기다려야 한다는 것을 기억합니다...
This problem has subsided.
이 문제는 가라앉았습니다.
But now...
그러나 지금...
It doesn't matter whether we are telling the truth or not.
우리가 진실을 말하고 있는지 아닌지 는 중요하지 않습니다 .
Ordinary people like us have no right to say anything.
우리 같은 평범한 사람들은 아무 말도 할 권리가 없습니다.
It's not our right to go back there...
거기로 돌아가는 건 우리의 권리가 아니야 ...
And drop the lawsuit.
그리고 소송을 취하하세요.
That is, after telling the truth...
즉, 사실을 말한 후에...
Do you still have to force yourself to come here?
아직도 억지로 여기 와야 해?
Just answer yes or no...
예, 아니오로만 대답하시면 됩니다 ...
I will handle the rest.
나머지는 제가 처리하겠습니다 .
I'll let you go...
내가 널 보내줄게...
As if I've never met you.
마치 내가 당신을 한 번도 만난 적이 없는 것처럼.
We will also guarantee safety..
안전 도 보장하겠습니다 ..
You and your family.
당신과 당신의 가족.
But if you cheat...
하지만 속이면...
I'll collect everything...
다 모아줄게...
Including families in border villages...
국경마을에 있는 가족들도 포함해서 ...
take questions
질문을 받다.
I swear...
맹세해요...
Everything I said earlier is true.
내가 아까 말한 것은 모두 사실이다.
just?
그냥?
Who knows?
누가 알아?
Let's go back to our village.
우리 마을로 돌아가자.
We can't make people angry here .
우리는 여기서 사람들을 화나게 할 수 없습니다 .
If I had known, I wouldn't have sent someone...
알았더라면 사람을 보내지 않았을텐데...
To investigate the useless boy.
쓸모없는 소년을 조사하기 위해.
We are looking for problems ourselves.
우리는 스스로 문제를 찾고 있습니다.
I am waiting for you.
나는 당신을 기다리고 있습니다.
why?
왜?
what's the matter?
왜 그래?
naught.
아무것도 아님.
Tell people to retreat.
사람들에게 후퇴하라고 말하세요.
I came to tell you this.
나는 이것을 말하려고 왔습니다.
I know you let him go.
당신이 그를 놓아준 걸 알아요.
Although I didn't write much in the letter...
비록 편지에는 별로 쓰지 않았지만...
And I can't give it to you...
그리고 줄 수도 없고...
Strong evidence...
강력한 증거...
Try hard...
열심히 노력해요...
To collect information.
정보를 수집하기 위해.
I understand you might be angry...
화내실 수도 있다는 건 이해해요...
But since you freed him...
하지만 당신이 그를 풀어준 이후로...
I came here to see you.
나는 당신을 만나러 여기에 왔습니다.
Did you hear it or not?
들었나요, 못 들었나요?
What are you wearing?
당신은 무엇을 입고 있나요?
Why does it smell normal?
왜 평범한 냄새가 나나요?
I don't use a tangagi.
저는 탕가기를 사용하지 않습니다.
Hua Chen.
화첸.
Please listen to me carefully .
제 말 을 잘 들어주세요 .
I don't feel well.
기분이 좋지 않아요.
I think I should go.
나는 가야 할 것 같아요.
I would like to avoid any further contact with you ...
더 이상 당신과의 접촉을 피하고 싶습니다 ...
So let's get it over with.
그러니 끝내자.
Then we won't have to meet again.
그러면 우리는 다시 만날 필요가 없습니다.
I've been thinking about it.
나는 그것에 대해 생각해 왔습니다.
Jong Ye-ran still likes you, but...
종예란은 아직도 당신을 좋아하지만...
I will not choose to run for office.
나는 출마를 선택하지 않을 것이다.
I will prove it to him...
나는 그에게 그것을 증명할 것이다 ...
Real people who care about him.
그를 걱정하는 실제 사람들 .
So you don't have to let me have him.
그러니 내가 그를 갖게 해줄 필요는 없어요 .
Why can't I forget this?
왜 이것을 잊을 수 없습니까 ?
I can't let you have him.
나는 당신이 그를 가질 수 없습니다.
He chose you.
그는 당신을 선택했습니다.
He did that on our wedding night.
그는 우리 결혼식 밤에 그런 일을 했습니다.
That person did it again...
그 사람이 또 그랬어...
The day I returned to my parents' house.
부모님 집으로 돌아오던 날 .
He did the same thing on the cliff.
그는 절벽에서도 같은 일을 했습니다 .
Even now, he hasn't changed.
지금도 그는 변하지 않았습니다.
I completely lost my mind...
나 완전 정신을 놔 버렸어...
I make mistakes...
실수도 하고...
But your brother is guilty too.
하지만 네 형도 죄가 있어.
I understand now.
지금은 이해.
Many aspects of our world involve ambiguous issues.
이 세상의 많은 부면에는 모호한 문제가 관련되어 있습니다.
Everyone has their own opinion...
다들 각자의 의견이 있는데..
About what is right and what is wrong.
무엇이 옳고 무엇이 그른지에 대해.
Even though my family refused...
가족들이 거부했는데도..
I will never do anything to the Hua family again .
나는 다시는 Hua 가족 에게 아무 짓도 하지 않을 것입니다 .
As long as you don't step on my toes...
네가 내 발을 밟지 않는 한...
I will assume you are a foreigner.
나는 당신이 외국인이라고 생각할 것입니다.
great.
좋아요.
Finally, I would like to give you some advice.
마지막으로 몇 가지 조언을 드리고 싶습니다.
I don't know how you can get involved with that guy...
당신이 그 사람과 어떻게 엮일 수 있는지 모르겠어요 ...
But since we know each other...
하지만 우리는 아는 사이라서...
take my advice
내 조언을 들어라
No matter how hard I tried, I couldn't find any evidence.
아무리 노력해도 아무런 증거도 찾지 못했습니다 .
There is no way to prove that he did it.
그가 그랬다는 것을 증명할 방법은 없습니다 .
Even if I end up divorcing Yellen...
결국 옐런과 이혼해도..
For your family...
가족을 위해...
But high status is uncertain...
하지만 높은 지위는 불확실하다...
You'll probably die before you can enjoy the results.
결과를 즐기기 전에 아마 죽을 것입니다 .
let's go.
갑시다.
Follow me to jail tomorrow.
내일 나를 따라 감옥에 가세요.
Okay, ma'am.
좋아요, 부인.
Why did you come again?
왜 또 왔나요?
It's dirty here.
이곳은 더럽습니다.
I met Mr. and Mrs. Lee.
나는 리 부부를 만났다.
I am the one who implicated you.
나는 당신을 연루시킨 사람입니다.
But don't worry...
하지만 걱정하지 마세요...
I promise I'll get you out of jail...
널 감옥에서 꺼내줄 거라고 약속할게 ...
Whatever the outcome.
결과가 어떻든 간에.
What does it mean...
무슨 뜻이에요...
Do I mean a lot to you?
내가 당신에게 큰 의미가 있나요?
Yes, it makes a lot of sense.
네, 매우 의미가 있습니다.
I banished Cuizhu.
나는 Cuizhu를 추방했습니다.
That's none of my business.
그건 내 알 바가 아니야.
Why did you tell me?
왜 나한테 말했어?
Suddenly you feel angry.
갑자기 당신은 화가 났습니다.
Qianzhi is getting married.
Qianzhi가 결혼합니다.
You are the only one by my side...
내 곁에는 너뿐이야...
When the time comes.
때가되면.
When released...
석방되면...
Me and my parents...
나와 내 부모님..
You can also leave Hwangcheong.
황청을 떠날 수도 있다.
We will not return to our village with pride .
우리는 자부심을 가지고 마을로 돌아가지 않을 것입니다 .
We will not bring many slaves.
우리는 노예를 많이 데려오지 않을 것이다.
We don't have much money either.
우리도 돈이 별로 없어요.
Maybe we don't have a place to live...
어쩌면 우리가 살 곳이 없을지도 모르지 ...
Or enough food.
아니면 충분한 음식.
Do you still want to come with me?
아직도 나와 함께 가고 싶니?
I don't chase fame or money...
나는 명예나 돈을 쫓지 않는다...
While working at Ms.
Ms.에서 일하는 동안
So no matter what happens...
그러니까 무슨 일이 있어도...
I'm not going...
난 안 갈 거야...
Even if you want to fire me.
당신이 나를 해고하고 싶어도.
tell me something
나한테 뭔가 말해봐
If there was a road ahead...
앞에 길이 있었다면...
It is full of uncertainty and difficulties.
불확실성과 어려움 으로 가득 차 있습니다 .
Everyone told me not to continue...
다들 계속하지 말라고 하더군요...
Should I be here...
나 여기 있어야 하나...
Or would you rather choose a different path?
아니면 다른 길을 선택하시겠습니까?
I'm stupid. Why am I telling you?
내가 바보. 내가 왜 당신에게 말하고 있습니까?
Because it is a path full of uncertainty ...
불확실성이 가득한 길이기 때문에 ...
It's a good idea to go back while you can.
할 수 있을 때 돌아가는 것이 좋습니다 .
I said so...
나는 그렇게 말했다...
Because I don't want to see you suffer .
왜냐하면 나는 당신이 고통받는 것을 보고 싶지 않기 때문입니다 .
It doesn't matter which path you choose...
어떤 길을 선택해도 상관은 없습니다...
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께있을 것입니다.
Kediaman Hua
케디아만 후아
Save everything.
모든 것을 저장하세요.
Isn’t this what Master Hwayoung said?
이거 화영 스승님의 말씀이 아닌가요 ?
Don't want to wear it anymore?
더 이상 입고 싶지 않으세요?
Keep it in your heart first.
먼저 가슴에 담아두세요.
There is a jewel in the dresser.
서랍장에 보석이 있어요 .
I will use...
나는 사용할 것이다 ...
One day, later.
어느 날, 나중에.
Miss Hwang sent me this earlier.
미스 황 씨가 아까 이걸 보냈어요.
Mr. Hwang said this is money...
황씨는 이게 돈이라고 하더군요...
Previous store sale.
이전 매장 판매.
You completed the work faster than I expected.
생각보다 빨리 작업을 완료해주셨네요 .
How is your relationship with Nanfeng ?
Nanfeng과의 관계는 어떻습니까 ?
I plan to go...
나는 갈 계획이다...
After seeing you get married.
당신이 결혼하는 걸 보고 나서요.
Don't tease me, girl.
놀리지 마세요, 아가씨.
I'm just asking
그냥 물어보는 거야
Why did you run away?
왜 도망쳤어?
Is there anyone you like?
좋아하는 사람 있니
no. no one.
아니요. 아무도.
Qianzhi has a sharp tongue...
Qianzhi는 날카로운 혀를 가지고 있습니다 ...
And it always annoys other people.
그리고 항상 다른 사람들을 귀찮게 합니다.
any...
어느...
Other helpers also like to cause trouble.
다른 도우미들도 문제를 일으키는 것을 좋아합니다.
I always worry about them.
나는 항상 그들에 대해 걱정합니다.
Among my maids...
내 하녀들 중에...
You are the calmest.
당신은 가장 침착합니다.
I can always count on you to get the job done.
나는 항상 당신이 일을 해낼 것이라고 믿을 수 있습니다 .
Do you have any plans for the future?
미래에 대한 계획이 있나요 ?
I would be happy to serve you .
당신을 섬길 수 있다면 기쁘겠습니다 .
You can't marry me, can you?
당신은 나와 결혼할 수 없어요, 그렇죠?
How can you be with me...?
어떻게 나랑 같이 있을 수 있어...?
forever?
평생?
don't worry. What I gave Qianzhi...
걱정 하지마. 내가 Qianzhi에게 무엇을 주었는지...
You will get it too.
당신도 그것을 얻을 것이다.
It's not easy for you...
너에겐 쉽지 않구나...
all the time you are with me
당신이 나와 함께 있는 모든 시간
I know it may be sudden...
갑작스러울 수도 있다는 걸 알아요...
But there's still time. This is the way.
하지만 아직 시간이 있어요. 이것이 방법입니다.
I'll give you two days to think about it...
이틀 동안 생각할 시간을 드릴게요 ...
what you want
당신이 원하는 것
Please tell me after you think about it.
생각하신 후에 말씀해주세요 .
If I could make your wish come true, I would.
당신의 소원을 이뤄줄 수 있다면 그렇게 할게요.
Lakaman Bonus
라카만 보너스
How much...
얼마나 많이...
You don't have to worry about Hua Rongzhou.
Hua Rongzhou에 대해 걱정할 필요가 없습니다 .
I'll handle it.
내가 처리할게.
When we got home...
우리가 집에 도착했을 때...
Go and find the house manager.
가서 집 관리인을 찾아보세요.
Get money and sign a contract..
돈받고 계약하세요..
Then go from here.
그럼 여기서 가세요.
I can let you go for what you did...
네가 한 짓에 대해선 널 놓아줄 수 있어 ...
But I can't have you by my side anymore.
하지만 난 더 이상 당신을 내 곁에 둘 수 없어요 .
Lady, I am guilty.
아가씨, 저는 유죄입니다.
I will accept any punishment.
어떤 처벌도 달게 받겠습니다.
I don't want my money or my contract.
나는 내 돈이나 계약을 원하지 않습니다.
Please let me stay here until guard Hua comes out ...
경비병 Hua가 나올 때까지 여기에 머물게 해주세요 ...
Please come home safely.
집에 무사히 오세요.
After that you can sell me.
그 후에는 나를 팔 수 있습니다.
How much...
얼마나 많이...
It's up to you.
당신한테 달렸습니다.
But I don't want to see you again.
하지만 난 당신을 다시 보고 싶지 않아요.
As expected...
예상대로...
People always make mistakes...
사람은 항상 실수를 합니다...
When driven by love
사랑에 이끌릴 때